Guide to the Rodolfo R. Schuller papers, ca. 1925-1932.
Schuller, Rodolfo R. papers,ca. 1925-1932.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Rodolfo R. Schuller papers, ca. 1925-1932.
9172
Rodolfo R., Schuller 1873-1932.
6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Vocabulary collection on Central and South American languages. Includes correspondence between Schuller and other members of the Museum of the Native American regarding the collection. Five boxes of 3x5 index cards with vocabulary items noted along with bibliographic source or notations in other languages. Six boxes boxes of half sheets with vocabulary items, words, definition, and pronunciation, organized by "root" or what appears to be subject in some cases. A note from Schuller says that this is a comparative dictionary of Maya Quiche and Carib-Aruak containing 40,000 words of all known dialects. Two boxes of manuscripts, notes for publications, and other vocabularies. Includes comparative vocabularies, grammar information, phonetic transcriptions, and glossaries of Mayan and Cholti languages. Published items including dictionaries and texts regarding Central American languages, some in Spanish. Index included in Box L.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Rodolfo or Rudolph, Schuller was a linguist who studied Mexican, Central and Southern American Indians. He served on the faculty of the National University in Mexico City. A large collection of his ethnological studies and photographs were acquired by Tulane University, in the 1920s shortly after Schuller moved to New Orleans. The papers are held in their Latin American Library.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Vocabulary collection on Central and South American languages. Includes correspondence between Schuller and other members of the Museum of the Native American regarding the collection. Five boxes of 3x5 index cards with vocabulary items noted along with bibliographic source or notations in other languages. Six boxes boxes of half sheets with vocabulary items, words, definition, and pronunciation, organized by "root" or what appears to be subject in some cases. A note from Schuller says that this is a comparative dictionary of Maya Quiche and Carib-Aruak containing 40,000 words of all known dialects. Two boxes of manuscripts, notes for publications, and other vocabularies. Includes comparative vocabularies, grammar information, phonetic transcriptions, and glossaries of Mayan and Cholti languages. Published items including dictionaries and texts regarding Central American languages, some in Spanish. Index included in Box L.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schuller, Rodolfo R.,1873-1932.; Hodge, Frederick Webb, 1864-1956.; La Farge, Oliver; McDougall, Elsie.; Tozzer, Alfred M.(Alfred Marston), 1877-1954.; Huntington Free Library.
Titles:
Popol vuh.
Subjects:
Indians of North America.; Indians of Mexico.; Indians of Mexico--Languages.; Indians of Central America.; Indians of Central America--Languages.; Indians of Central America--Dictionaries.; Indians of the West Indies.; Indians of the West Indies--Languages.; Indians of South America.; Arawak Indians.; Arawak language.; Arhuaco Indians.; Carib Indians.; Carib language.; Chol Indians.; Chol language.; Ica language.; Linguistics.; Matlatzinca Indians.; Matlatzinca language.; Mayas.; Mayan languages.; Totonac Indians.; Totonac language.; Quiché Indians.; Quiché language.; Xinca Indians.; Xinca language.
Places:
Caldas (Colombia: Dept.); Central America; Columbia.; Giatemala.; Latin America--History.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Vocabulary organized by root
Boxes 10A-F
Series II. Vocabulary cards with bibliographic information
Boxes 10G-K
Series III. Papers and Correspondence
Boxes 10L-M
Series IV. Printed Material
Boxes 10M
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Vocabulary organized by root
  Folder titles of the vocabulary are not all inclusive and are copied directly without verification of their contents. Due to poor handwriting on the folders there may be errors in spelling. Folder titles are made up of a "root" and contain words using that "root", followed by English definitions. There seems to be no order at all in any of the vocabularies and the folder titles have vague relationships to their contents. Presuming original order of the material has been maintained this would appear to be a naming and ordering system that only Schuller understood.
  - Vus-kus, round-full, Vo-Kua (Box 10A)
  - Mul-pul, to congregate round (Box 10A)
  - Ul-ol-ur-or-il, ir-el-er (Box 10A)
  - Ub-up-pup-uba, hollow, round, blowing (Box 10A)
  - Up-op-pop, to congregate (Box 10A)
  - Mu-pu-po, celestial bodies (Box 10A)
  - Pu-po, celestial body (Box 10A)
  - Ama, ma, vua, maize and related ideas (Box 10B)
  - Ong-ung-eng-kung, etc, hollow-round (Box 10B)
  - Ib-ip, force, strength (Box 10B)
  - Is, to see, sight, eagle, bird, and so forth (Box 10B)
  - Ui-vui-hui (Box 10B)
  - Pa-pam-ap-apa (Box 10B)
  - Ek, black, cold, and related ideas (Box 10B)
  - Eu, teu cold; ras, fresh green etc. (Box 10B)
  - Co-tsu-su, might, black, cold (Box 10B)
  - Lum, earth and related ideas (Box 10B)
  - Ku-kuk-kok, recipient (Box 10B)
  - Different Animals (Box 10B)
  - Ka-ca-koi-cai-tsa-ka, tsa ta, sa, fish and so on (Box 10B)
  - Bibliography (Box 10C)
  - Tan, ak, kat, hol, fire and related ideas (Box 10C)
  - Kui, tree, hui fruits, flower, mountain, Maya (Box 10C)
  - Ki-si-ci-tsi, hot, sun, fire, tree, forest, etc. (Box 10C)
  - Ok-uk, us, is, to drink, throat, recipient (Box 10C)
  - Uh-ux-uk, to drink, smoke, breatje, to kiss and so on (Box 10C)
  - Su-tsu-cu-tsi (Box 10C)
  - Tel, ter (Box 10D)
  - Ethnography: dress (Box 10D)
  - mats, serpent, snake (Box 10D)
  - to, so, dug (Box 10D)
  - pek, s-pek, toad, frog, tortoise (Box 10D)
  - ala, sala, snake serpent (Box 10D)
  - koi-sui, rabbit, hare (Box 10D)
  - Uk-um, dove (Box 10D)
  - Pets, etc., duck, goose, zanate (Box 10D)
  - am, spider (Box 10D)
  - xex, fly, mosquito (Box 10D)
  - cic, iron (Box 10D)
  - ma, negative (Box 10D)
  - Mem, mo, dumb, stupid, silly (Box 10D)
  - Aur, corn, nose (Box 10D)
  - Cil, hair, beard (Box 10D)
  - Ti, meat, eat, mouth (Box 10D)
  - Pathology, sickness and so on (Box 10D)
  - ia, ya, was, quas, iya, water (Box 10D)
  - Lem, thunder, thunderbolt, flash, etc. (Box 10D)
  - Hen-mem, flash of (Box 10D)
  - Kap-kop, word, language (Box 10D)
  - Garrot (Box 10D)
  - Ik-uk-sik-suk, wing, point, top (Box 10D)
  - Ni, nose, point (Box 10D)
  - Mai, tobacco (Box 10D)
  - Gi, blood, sap, juice, sweat (Box 10D)
  - Ki-kik-ik-ic, blood (Box 10D)
  - Ut-tut-ot-tot (Box 10D)
  - Kot ko akat, dance, drum, mask (Box 10D)
  - Ma, celestial bodies (Box 10D)
  - Thunder, lightning, rain, storm, and related ideas (Box 10D)
  - At, ata, had, hot, sun, tree, wood, house (Box 10D)
  - Different Maya Kice (Box 10E)
  - Differnt Karib Arawak (Box 10E)
  - Plants (Box 10E)
  - Family and Affinity (Box 10E)
  - Tir-Ter (Box 10E)
  - BLV (Box 10E)
  - Al (Box 10E)
  - Al, recipient (Box 10E)
  - Bi-pe-be-pi, bin-pin-bu-bo (Box 10E)
  - San Jose (Box 10F)
  - Im-imu, mu-mu-ru (Box 10F)
  - Tir, Ter (Box 10F)
  - Ka-ch-tsa-sa, Ke-ki, stone, bone, hard, etc., ak-hag, xak, ok, uk, ek, ik (Box 10F)
  - Ak, stone (Box 10F)
  - Ca-sa, stone, hard, bone, tooth, and so on (Box 10F)
  - Ka, stone, bone, hard (Box 10F)
  - Sa, stone, tooth, earth, bone, hard (Box 10F)
  - Ca, stone, bone, hard (Box 10F)
  - Bak-pak, hard, bone, puak-poka (Box 10F)
  - Tsa-tsap-tso-tsop-tsu (Box 10F)
  - pac, pok, pox, po, stone, bone, hard, mud, etc. (Box 10F)
  - Ot-oc-ots, bone, hard, stone, etc. (Box 10F)
  - Ots-ok to enter (Box 10F)
  - Ko, co, stone, bone, hard (Box 10F)
  - Ok-uk, ots, oc, stone, bone, hard, etc. (Box 10F)
  - E, te, ek,ok, ce-ke, et, tet, it, cen-ken, gen, stone, tooth, earth, hard, bone, cave (Box 10F)
  - En, tsen, kill, mountain (Box 10F)
  - To, tu, stone (Box 10F)
  - Tun, ton, tu, stone (Box 10F)
  - Yu-ub, huy-ub (Box 10F)
  - Ka-ak-aka-aga, ca, akal, agal, sa, akua, gua, tsa, kua, gua (Box 10F)
  - Ko, ok, ku, tso, ots, uk, yo, kuk, xu, so, su, to, tu (Box 10F)
  - Ku-uk, up (Box 10F)
  - Ke, to, ye-he, ki, ti, yi (Box 10F)
  - Te (Box 10F)
  - Ap-tap-lak (Box 10F)
  - Ta-tan (Box 10F)
  - Guatuso The making pottery (Box 10F)
- Series II. Vocabulary cards with bibliographic information (Box 10G-10K)
  3x5 cards of vocabulary, subject, and names. Divided into unlabeled sections with no apparent or decipherable order.
- Series III. Papers and Correspondence
  - Index, printed guides, calendars for the collection. Provenance information. (Box 10L, Folder 1)
  - Lists of materials offered for sale by Schuller; correspondence between Schuller and Hodge re the acquisition of the collection, etc. (Box 10L, Folder 1)
  - Biographic info and old index. (Box 10L, Folder 1.1)
    Includes photos of Schuller.
  - Microfilm sequence index (Box 10L, Folder 1.2)
  - About 5,000 words taken from each one of the known Maya-K'ice (Quiche) languages. A semantic study of different archaic Maya- K'ice forms. (Box 10L, Folder 2, 2.1)
    434 large sheets. A few have notes on versos, a few inserted small sheets.
  - Maya-K'ice elements in a series of Karib-Aruak (Arawak) languages, embracing the archaic forms in all known Maya-K'ice tongues. (Box 10L, Folder 3)
    138 large sheets.
  - Comparative Maya-K'ice glossary. (Box 10L, Folder 4)
    152 sheets. Materials taken from Stoll, Rockstroh, Sapper, and so forth, each sheet dedicated to a particular word (man, woman, etc.) with definitions for 1-22A [languages?] on each sheet.
  - Spanish-Totonaca glossary (Box 10L, Folder 5)
    77 sheets, unpublished. Compiled from a manuscript in the possession of Tulane University.
  - Extract of the Doctrina Christiana in the Mexican Indian language (Box 10L, Folder 5)
    9 sheets, at the end of the above Spaish-Totonaca glossary. Annotated by R. Schuller.
  - Maya-K'ice studies, mostly a linguistic comparison of Maya-K'ice forms with the respect. (Box 10L, Folder 6)
    96 large sheets. Includes: Archaic roots Mixe-Ayook (Balimar) p.1-8. Maya-K'ice studies: Sexual parts p.9-11; U1- atole, and related ideas p.12-13; Roots: Ac-aci, etc. p.14-23; Vocabulary from Steinen, Leipzig 1892 p.24-28; Roots: Kua, etc. p.29-49; Extracts from Steinen, Greenberg p.50-59; Extracts from the Motul Maya dictionary (ms, Peabody Museum, Harvard) p. 60-78; Extracts from "Brebe Noticia de 10s vocablos mas usuales de la lengua Kakchiquel," Peabody Museum ms. p.79-96.
  - A study of the linguistic map of Hondorus, C.A., according to Indian geographical nomenclature. (Box 10L, Folder 7)
    187 sheets, containing several thousand Indian place names. Materials gathered by R. Schuller in 1927 which were to be published to show the geographical distribution of the different Indian languages of Honduras.
  - Extracts made from Membreño, Alberto. Nombres Geográficos Indigenas de la República de Honduras. 1901. 26p. (Box 10L, Folder 7.1, 7.2)
  - Guia de Agrimensores o sea Recopilacion de Leyes Agrarias. Por Antonio Vallejo. Tegucigalpa. Tipografia Nacional. Avenida Cervantes Número 42. 1911. (Box 10L, Folder 7.3)
  - Maya K'ice. Lenca-Karib-Arawak (Box 10L, Folder 8)
    43 sheets
  - Maya-K'ice elements in Zoque-Mixe taken from Lenguas Indigenas de Centro America by Ferraz y Fernandez Guardia (Box 10L, Folder 8.1)
    19 sheets
  - Mam glossary taken from Arte y Vocabulario de la lengua Mame by Father Diego de Reynoso (Box 10L, Folder 8.2)
    21 sheets with annotations.
  - Additions to Stoll's Aguacateca glossary (Box 10L, Folder 8.3)
    7 sheets
  - Comparative Vocabularies of different Maya-K'ice Dialects (Box 10L, Folder 8.4)
    9 sheets. Four languages, Aguacateca, Mam, Jacalteca, Cuxe.
  - Extracts of Stoll's Ixil tract, a Maya-K'ice language (Box 10L, Folder 9)
    61 sheets with annotations by Schuller.
  - Contribucción a1 Estudio de Las Lenguas Aborigines de El Salvador. (Especialmente de la antigua Provincia de Chaparrastique-San Miguel), por Rudolf Schuller. (Box 10L, Folder 9.1)
    54 sheets.
  - Pipil poetry and a short vocabulary from El Salvador, C.A. (Box 10L, Folder 10)
    Obtained from an Indian of Izalco, 1925.
  - Facsimile of the Pineda Map of America, 1519. (Box 10L, Folder 11)
    From Navarrete "Coleccion de Documentos". Madrid.
  - On the value of the Spanish money (coins) and weight of the earlier part of the 16th century. (Box 10L, Folder 12)
    Notebook titled Medidas Pesos Moneda with inserts. Compiled by R. Schuller according the most reliable sources of information.
  - Correspondenz über den Historiographen Ulrich Schmiedel. (Box 10L, Folder 12)
    Letters, unpubl., on the historian Ulrich Schmiedel between R. Schuller and Dr. Mondschein of Straubing, the birthplace of that famous chronicler of the first and the most important Spanish settlement in the countries of River Platte, (1535-1555.)
  - Notes on Uspanteca (Pokonchi dialect) of Guatemala. (Box 10L, Folder 14)
  - Notes on the Tzotzil language of Chiapas. (Box 10L, Folder 14.1)
    According to Jose Maria Sanchez, 1895 and others, 21 sheets.
  - Notes on the linguistic map of El Salvador, C.A. (Box 10L, Folder 14.2)
  - Notes mostly geographical, or place-names of Indian origin. (Box 10L, Folder 14.3)
    Unpublished, 10 large sheets.
  - Extracts from Father Beltrán, Maya grammar. (Box 10L, Folder 14.4)
    1859 (2nd edition) with notes by R. Sch. 40 sheets.
  - Extract from a very short Trique glossary, with place names in Mexican and in Trique (native tongue of Oaxaca). (Box 10L, Folder 15)
  - Modo deaprender la lengua Ixil. (Box 10L, Folder 16)
    Copy of an unpubl. ms. fragment dealing with the Ixil language, a Maya- K'ice dialect of Guatemala, C.A. 10 sheets with notes by R. Sch.
  - Folklore: Native poetry of South America including Bolivia. (Box 10L, Folder 17)
    148 sheets collected during many years in South America partly from very scarce broad-sides, and partly from mss. sources.
  - Grammar and vocabulary 1685-1695 from Moran, Francisco. Art en lengua Ch'olti, 1695. (Box 10L, Folder 18-18.5)
    Annotated copy of ms. in Gates collection, Tulane University. Also included: parts of the human body; Indian community, family and so forth; ethnography; nature; adjective attributive; verbs; participles; colours.
  - 29 negatives of the famous collection of gold objects from burial-places in Caldas, the Quimbaya region of Central Colombia, S.A. (Box 10L, Folder 19)
  - 13 Maps of different Middle American republics, from Petermanns Geographische Mitteilungen. (Box 10L, Folder 20)
    Maps are folded and are large. Maps by Dr. Carl Sapper.
  - Unpublished Barbacoa glossary. (Box 10L, Folder 21)
    Taken by R. Sch. at Popayan, Southern Colombia, S.A.
  - Place names of southern Colombia, all of Indian origin, elements for a linguistic chart of that section of Colombia. (Box 10L, Folder 21)
  - Geographical names, mostly of the Choco languages of central and western Colombia. (Box 10L, Folder 21)
  - A Choco glossary (Box 10L, Folder 21)
    From a scarce printed book by Uribe
  - List of place names of Indian origin of northern Colombia, Cartagena. (Box 10L, Folder 21)
  - Notes on the relationship of the Xinca language of Guatemala to Maya-K'ice. (Box 10L, Folder 22)
    Unpublished linguistic comparisons, with notes which the author intended to publish but left unfinished.
  - An unpublished account made in Latin by the Jesuit Father Sanmartoni (Szehtmartony) (Box 10L, Folder 23)
    A Hungarian, former astronomer of the Indians of the Jesuit Missions on the Upper Amazon and its tributaries. XVIII century. Original preserved at the National Library, Rio de Janeiro. See Catalogo da Exposigao Brazileira.
  - Notes on entirely unknown Indian languages of Ecuador, S.A. (Box 10L, Folder 24)
    Gathered by R. Schuller, from "Relaciones Geograficas."
  - Catalina II, the Empress of Russia, and her relations to American linguistics. (Box 10L, Folder 25)
    Notes on a very scarcely known document.
  - On the Motilon Indians, of Western Venezuela. (Box 10L, Folder 26)
    Unpublished ms. copies by R. Schuller (1910) in the Deposito Hidrografico, Madrid.
  - Relacion del Alto Orinoco. (Box 10L, Folder 27)
    Unpublished ms. from the Munoz Collection, Madrid. Copied by R. Schuller. 1910.
  - Fragment of Betoye Glossary. (Box 10L, Folder 28)
    Unknown if this was published. 5 sheets (Segue o vocabulario do Rio Putumayo).
  - Fragment of Karth Glossary from Upper Orinoco. (Box 10L, Folder 29)
    Unpublished ms. copied by R. Schuller, 1910, Madrid. (Idioma Carihe de Cuando estuve en el Orinoco).
  - Copy of a Matlatzinca vocabulary (Box 10M, Folder 30-30.10)
    From the handwritten annotations in Vocabulario en lengua Castelland y Mexicans, 1555 by Alonso de Molina. 1544 sheets.
  - Photostat of mss. "A List of the Native Languages of the Latin American Countries," (Box 10M, Folder 31)
    Compiled by Dr. Rudolph R. Schuller.
  - A list of the Native Languages of the Latin American Countries. (Box 10M, Folder 32)
    Typescript compiled by Dr. Rudolph R. Schuller. Includes correspondence from T. Franklin Currier of Harvard College Library.
  - Misc. correspondence and newspaper clippings. (Box 10M, Folder 45)
    Includes letters from A. Breton, 1912, 1913, 1914. List of folio contents of ms J. 92 in Biblioteca National and letters from staff members there. List of contents of folios of unidentified ms. from Ville de Besançon, Bibliothéque Publique made by George Gazier, conservateur and letters from staff there. News clippings about Schuller.
- Series IV. Printed Material
  Folders with reprints of Schuller's scientific papers and others, partially annotated by Schuller
  - Repertorio Americano vol. 16, no. 22, 1928 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
  - Repertorio Americano vol. 17, no. 3, 1928 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
  - El Maestro vol. 1, nos. 5 and 6. (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    "La posicion etnologica de los indios de Talamanca, Costa Rica, C. A, por Rodolfo Schuller"
  - Buschmann, J. C. E. (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    One typed sheet of titles by this author.
  - Anales del Museo Nacional de Arqueologia, Historia y Etnografia vol. 1, no. 2., 1925 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    "La lengua Chinanteca del estado Oaxaca, por Rudolf Schuller."
  - Schuller Rudolf Revista Americana vol. 1, no. 9., 1910 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    "Um livro americano unico."
  - Lehmann, Walter Revista Americana, 1909 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    "Problemas Americanistas"
  - Schuller, Rudolph Journal of American Folk-Lore vol. 28, no. 60, 1915 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    "Native poetry of northern Brazil"
  - Schuller, Rudolph Journal of American Folk-Lore, vol. 26, no. 52, 1913 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    "Paraquay native poetry"
  - Schuller, Rudolpho R. Boletim do Museu Goeldi, vol. 6, 1906 (Box 10M, Folder 33)
    "A Couvade"
  - Schuller, Rudolfo R, Revista de Archivas, Bibliotecas y Museos, 1912 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "Linguistica Americana: notas Bibliograficas" with correspondence.
  - Schuller, Rudolph Archivos del Folklore Cubano, vol. 4, no. 2, 1929 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "El huracán; dios de la tormenta, y el Popol-Vuh"
  - Schuller, Rudolph Anales Universitarios, vol. 1, no. 4, 1928 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "La organizatión de la familia de los pueblos mas primitives."
  - Casanova, P. González Anales del Museo Nacional de Arguelogia, Historia y Etnografias, vol. 1, no. 5, 1928 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "Los idiomas popolocas."
  - Fernandez, Miguel Angel Monumentos Arquelogicos, vol. 1, 1925 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "El juego de pelota de Chichen-Itza, Yucatan."
  - Casanova, P. González Anales del Museo Nacional de Arquelogia, Historia, y Etnografia, vol. 1, no. 1, 1925 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "Nota sobre la lengua Chinanteca."
  - Department of Middle American Research of the Tulane University of Louisiana Its Activites and Its Aims, September 1928 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
  - Schuller, Rudolph American Anthropologist, vol. 29, no. 2, 1927 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "The native country of the Maya-K'ice Indians"
  - American Anthropologist, vol. 18, no. 4 Discussion and correspondence, 1916 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    "Discovery of New Materials of the Moseten Idiom"
  - Anthropos: Revue Internationale d 'Ethnologie et de Linguistique, vol. 7, no. 6, 1912 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    Pages 987-1018.
  - Anthropos: Revue Internationale d 'Ethnologie et de Linguistique, vol. 8, nos. 2 and 3, 1913 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    Pages 365-396.
  - Anales Universitarios, vol. 1, no. 5 (Box 10M, Folder 33.1)
    Just the cover.
  - Bibliography sheets attributed to Schuller (Box 10M, Folder 33.2)
    Cards and typed half sheets. Half sheets cover 1904-1931 with entries of his publications arranged chronologically.
  - Seven extracts from newspapers. (Box 10M, Folder 34)
  - Photostats of title pages of manuscripts relating to Matlatzinca language (Box 10M, Folder 35)
    Copied from the original in the John Carter Brown Library.
  - Schuller, Rudolph The Oldest Known Illustration of South American Indians (Box 10M, Folder 36)
    Reprint from Indian Notes, vol. 7, no. 4, 1930. Associated letter from C. Wilberforce Eames, 12/14/30.
  - Morley, Sylvanus Griswold Congrés des Américanists, compte-rendu de la 21st session, 1925 (Box 10M, Folder 37)
    "The earliest Mayan dates." Published by the Göteborg Museum.. Signed by Frans Blom.
  - Palino, Celstino Vocabulario Totonaco, 1907 (Box 10M, Folder 38)
    Xalapa- Enriquez: Oficina tipografica del gobierno desestado.
  - Revista del Archivo y de la Biblioteca Nacional de Honduras, vol. 3, nos. 2-16, 1906-1907 (Box 10M, Folder 39)
    "El Popol Vuh"
  - Revista de etnología arquelogía, y lingüística, vol. 1, nos. 1 and 2, 1925 (Box 10M, Folder 40)
  - Drawings for proposed book plate. (Box 10M, Folder 41)
    Appear to be by Schuller for his own books.
  - Schuller, Rodolfo R. Accerca del "Yslario General" de Alonzo de Santa Cruz" (Box 10M, Folder 42)
    Extracted from the 18th International Congress of Americanists. Marshall H. Saville Collection.
  - A Nova Gazeta da Terra do Brasil (Newen Zeytunq auss Presillg Landt) e sua origem mais provavelu, 1914 (Box 10M, Folder 43)
    Published in Rio de Janeiro. Extr. do vol. 33 dos Annaes da Biblioteca Nacional. Includes a pasted in photograph of Schuller and annotations.
  - Schuller, Rudolf R. Zur affinitát der Tapúya-Indianer des 'Theatrum Rerum Naturalium Brasiliae, 1912 (Box 10M, Folder 44)